So now that we have entered the total
sales, total income and the average sales
data, we now need to go back to the Word
document to see what else is required.
And if we look on there, we are being
asked to show if the target sales of 250
for each product were met or not so that
they can look at adjusting our offers.
So this will require an IF statement and
an IF statement is quite straight forward.
It is a logical argument.
If something is equal to or greater than
or less than, it will simply display
a value of true, false or specific
element of text that you wish to display.
So, what we need to do first is
I'm going to give this column a new
heading, and it's going to be target
met and what we need to do then is
we need to decide in this column,
whether the target of 250 was met.
Now, the total sales is
indicated in column J.
So we need to reference that cell.
And depending on what that value
is, display either yes or no.
So to do that, we need to
insert an IF statement.
So to do that, I've clicked on that cell.
And if we go to the formulas and then
select insert function, the insert
function, dialog box comes up and it
gives you a range of the most common
or most recently used formulas.
So we have SUMIF, subtotal, sum
average, IF, hyperlink, count.
So what we're looking
for is the IF statement.
So if I click on that and
then select OK it then brings
up the IF function argument.
So the logical test for this one
is that we need to say that the
sales are greater than 250 or not.
So the logical argument is that,
is that cell there, which is
J2, is that greater than 250.
So I would need to use
the greater than symbol.
And then the number 250.
So if that is greater than 250, what
do I want it to say if it's true?
And that is quite simply "yes".
And if the value is false, "no".
So if I now select OK
that will enter that.
And as you can see, it is yes.
And you can look at that and say,
yeah, well, 378, greater than 250.
So it should be, yes.
This is important in relation to the
fact that you may have an awful lot
of data, you could have 500 entries
and quite simply rather than having to
look at each of them, you could simply
filter out for the yes and the nos.
So again, as mentioned in the previous
videos, I can just copy that formula
down by clicking in the bottom corner.
And when it changes to a black
crosshair, just moving it down.
And as you can see there, there
were two items that did sell
over 250 and three that didn't.
Obviously you can just look
here and see that for yourself.
But as I say, if you had a large
amount of data or this was needed to
reference something else, it would be
quite complicated, so this simplifies
the process and allows you to see that
whether the target was met or not.
There are occasions where you may
need to use the SUMIF function
rather than just the IF function.
And that would be when you want to
calculate a certain number of cells
or certain cells that meet certain
criteria and then display certain
information in relation to that.
I have provided further detail on
the webpage with a link that you can
follow to look at the SUMIF function
in greater detail, but for the
purposes of this one, the IF statement
is what is required so that you can
confirm a simple yes or no argument.